Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod. My name is Marco and I'm Erika.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。我是Marco，我是Erika。
And today we're looking at some more romance. We're talking about dating.
今天我们继续聊浪漫话题，我们正在讨论约会。
Dating, exactly. And not only dating but asking someone to become your boyfriend or girlfriend.
约会，没错。而且不只是约会，还包括请求某人成为你的男朋友或女朋友。
Yep, that's true. And so we're going to be focusing on language to express your romantic feelings.
是的，没错。所以我们将重点学习表达浪漫情感的用语。
And also maybe some phrases you can use to ask someone out.
也许还有一些可以用来约某人出去的短语。
Very good. So I'm sure you guys are excited about this one. So let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
很好。我相信你们对这个话题很兴奋。那么让我们第一次听对话。
Hey, you're early. Where is everyone?
嘿，你来早了。其他人呢？
Well, I told them not to come. I made a reservation just for the two of us.
嗯，我告诉他们不用来了。我只订了我们两个人的位子。
I thought we could have a quiet evening all to ourselves.
我想我们可以独享一个安静的夜晚。
Oh, why?
哦，为什么？
Jennifer, there's something I want to ask you.
詹妮弗，我有件事想问你。
Sure, what is it?
当然，什么事？
Okay, here's the thing. I've always seen you as more than just a friend. And I can't take it anymore.
好吧，事情是这样的。我一直把你视为不仅仅是朋友。我再也受不了了。
I know you better than anyone. I know the pros and cons of your personality.
我比任何人都了解你。我知道你性格的优缺点。
I even know what side of the bed is yours. I think we would be great together, don't you?
我甚至知道你睡床的哪一边。我觉得我们在一起会很合适，你不觉得吗？
Are you serious? We've been friends for years. We can't just change that overnight.
你是认真的吗？我们做朋友好多年了。我们不能一夜之间就改变这个。
I know. I never had the guts to tell you. Until today.
我知道。我以前一直没勇气告诉你。直到今天。
So what do you say? Are you willing to give me a shot?
那你觉得呢？你愿意给我一次机会吗？
Alright, I wonder, is she going to say yes?
好吧，我想知道，她会答应吗？
I don't know. She seems a little bit confused.
我不知道。她看起来有点困惑。
Well, I guess it's always strange when your best friend suddenly wants to be your boyfriend or girlfriend.
嗯，我觉得当你最好的朋友突然想成为你的男朋友或女朋友时，总是有点奇怪。
It does happen though. It does happen.
不过这种事确实会发生。确实会发生。
So why don't we take a look at some of the vocabulary that was used in this dialogue to express these feelings.
那我们来看看这个对话中用来表达这些情感的一些词汇吧。
And let's start with Fluency Builder.
我们从流利度提升开始。
Okay, so we're doing things a little differently today.
好的，今天我们有点不同。
We're looking at phrases and not just vocabulary words.
我们看的是短语，而不仅仅是单词。
So he used some wonderful phrases to ask her to be his boyfriend.
所以他用了一些很棒的短语来请求她成为他的男朋友。
And he started with this. Here's the thing.
他一开始用了这个：事情是这样的。
Here's the thing.
事情是这样的。
Alright, that's a very strange phrase. Here's the thing. Is he giving her something?
好吧，这是个很奇怪的短语。事情是这样的。他要给她什么东西吗？
Not quite. He's not giving her an object. But he's giving her some information.
不完全是。他不是给她一个物品。但他要给她一些信息。
Okay, so it's a very common way to start an idea.
好的，所以这是一种很常见的开始表达想法的方式。
You're about to tell the person the main problem or the main piece of information.
你正要告诉对方主要问题或主要信息。
So you would start with, here's the thing, and then start explaining.
所以你会以“事情是这样的”开头，然后开始解释。
Okay, why don't we do an example?
好的，我们举个例子吧？
For example, you could say, alright, here's the thing. People don't like you.
比如，你可以说，好吧，事情是这样的。大家不喜欢你。
Alright, well I hope they don't say that to me.
好吧，我希望他们别对我说这个。
But another example. Marco, here's the thing. We're behind in our podcasting. We have to work overtime.
但另一个例子。Marco，事情是这样的。我们的播客进度落后了。我们得加班。
Okay, so the main idea.
好的，所以是主要意思。
Yep.
是的。
Very good. Moving on to our next phrase.
很好。继续看下一个短语。
He said, I can't take it.
他说，我受不了了。
I can't take it anymore.
我再也受不了了。
So he can't take it anymore. Take what?
所以他再也受不了了。受不了什么？
Well, why don't we find out by listening to some examples.
嗯，我们听一些例子来弄清楚吧。
Examples.
例子。
Example one.
例子一。
The man next door has been so loud. I can't take it anymore.
隔壁的男人太吵了。我再也受不了了。
Example two.
例子二。
My boss always yells at me. I can't take it anymore.
我老板总是对我大喊大叫。我再也受不了了。
Example three.
例子三。
I can't take it anymore. I'm going to quit.
我再也受不了了。我要辞职。
Alright, so basically is you can't stand it. You can't tolerate it anymore.
好吧，所以基本上就是你无法忍受。你再也无法容忍了。
Exactly. This is a phrase we use when we are really frustrated.
没错。这是我们非常沮丧时用的短语。
Yeah, when we're frustrated or when we just can't handle it anymore.
是的，当我们沮丧或实在应付不来的时候。
And well, after he finished his declaration of love, she responded by saying, are you serious?
嗯，在他表白之后，她回应说，你是认真的吗？
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗？
Okay, so what does she mean?
好的，她是什么意思？
She's just saying, really?
她只是在说，真的吗？
Exactly. It's another way of saying, really?
没错。这是“真的吗？”的另一种说法。
Yeah. So this is a phrase that's really, it's quite informal, isn't it?
是的。所以这个短语真的很……它相当非正式，对吧？
Yeah, I guess you wouldn't use it in a business context.
是的，我想你不会在商务场合用它。
No, and it's also something that's used mostly by younger people.
不，而且它主要也是年轻人用的。
Right. If you say something that's amazing or that's incredible, hard to believe, you might get this response.
对。如果你说了什么惊人的、难以置信的、难以相信的事，你可能会得到这个回应。
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗？
Right. So he is very serious, but he confessed that he never had the guts to tell her.
对。所以他非常认真，但他承认他以前从没勇气告诉她。
Have the guts.
有勇气。
I never had the guts to tell you.
我以前从没勇气告诉你。
I never had the guts.
我以前从没勇气。
Alright, so to have guts.
好吧，所以“有勇气”。
That's to be brave.
就是勇敢。
To be brave, courageous.
勇敢，有胆量。
Yep.
是的。
So we have some examples of how we would use guts in different situations, so let's listen.
所以我们有一些例子，说明在不同情况下如何使用“guts”，我们来听听。
Example one.
例子一。
I don't have the guts to go skydiving.
我没有勇气去跳伞。
Example two.
例子二。
I don't have the guts to give a speech.
我没有勇气发表演讲。
Example three.
例子三。
I've never had the guts to say no to my boss.
我从来没有勇气对老板说不。
Alright, so to have the guts to do something.
好吧，所以“有勇气做某事”。
Hey, but Marco, this word guts, it's an interesting one.
嘿，但是Marco，这个词“guts”挺有意思的。
Yes, it is, because guts can also mean your internal organs.
是的，没错，因为“guts”也可以指你的内脏。
Like your stomach and your intestines and your lungs.
比如你的胃、肠和肺。
Exactly, those are your guts.
没错，那些就是你的内脏。
Yep, so when you have guts, you're really brave.
是的，所以当你有“guts”时，你真的很勇敢。
Exactly, you're courageous.
没错，你很有胆量。
Alright, very good. Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the second time.
好的，很好。我们第二次听对话吧。
We're going to slow it down a little bit, and we'll come back and look at some phrases and putting it together.
我们会放慢一点速度，然后回来看看一些短语并整合起来。
Hey, you're early. Where's everyone?
嘿，你来早了。其他人呢？
Well, I told them not to come. I made a reservation just for the two of us. I thought we could have a quiet evening all to ourselves.
嗯，我告诉他们不用来了。我只订了我们两个人的位子。我想我们可以独享一个安静的夜晚。
Oh, why?
哦，为什么？
Jennifer, there's something I want to ask you.
詹妮弗，我有件事想问你。
Sure, what is it?
当然，什么事？
Okay, here's the thing. I've always seen you as more than just a friend, and I can't take it anymore.
好吧，事情是这样的。我一直把你视为不仅仅是朋友，我再也受不了了。
I know you better than anyone. I know the pros and cons of your personality. I even know what side of the bed is yours.
我比任何人都了解你。我知道你性格的优缺点。我甚至知道你睡床的哪一边。
I think we would be great together, don't you?
我觉得我们在一起会很合适，你不觉得吗？
Are you serious? We've been friends for years. We can't just change that overnight.
你是认真的吗？我们做朋友好多年了。我们不能一夜之间就改变这个。
I know. I've never had the guts to tell you until today. So, what do you say? Are you willing to give me a shot?
我知道。我以前一直没勇气告诉你直到今天。那你觉得呢？你愿意给我一次机会吗？
I... I...
我……我……
Alright, that's a little bit clearer this time. But while I was listening, I noticed that there's some more great phrases that you can use together with different words.
好吧，这次清楚一点了。但我在听的时候，注意到还有一些很棒的短语可以和其他词搭配使用。
So, let's look at those now and putting it together.
那么，我们现在来看看这些，并整合起来。
Alright, let's take a look at the first one. He said, I made a reservation just for the two of us.
好的，我们来看第一个。他说，我只订了我们两个人的位子。
The two of us?
我们两个人？
Just the two of us.
就我们两个人。
So, just the two of us. Quite simply, it means you and me. Just us, right?
所以，“就我们两个人”。很简单，意思就是“你和我”。就我们，对吧？
Right. Just us. So, why is this phrase important?
对。就我们。那为什么这个短语重要呢？
I think it's a great way to show the idea of only us, right?
我认为这是一个很好的方式来表达“只有我们”的概念，对吧？
Right.
对。
And we can use it together with any number we want.
而且我们可以把它和任何我们想要的数字搭配使用。
So, what about the four of us?
那“我们四个人”呢？
Just the four of us. Just the eight of us. So, it suggests the idea of only us.
就我们四个人。就我们八个人。所以它暗示了“只有我们”的概念。
So, he made the reservation just for the two of us because he thought they could have a quiet evening all to ourselves.
所以他只订了我们两个人的位子，因为他觉得他们可以独享一个安静的夜晚。
All to ourselves.
完全属于我们自己。
If you have something all to yourself or we have something all to ourselves.
如果你完全拥有某样东西，或者我们完全拥有某样东西。
We have that thing all alone. We don't have to share it.
我们独自拥有那样东西。我们不需要分享它。
We don't share. Very good.
我们不分享。很好。
So, I guess you can say, my parents are out of town, so I have the apartment, I have the house all to myself.
所以，我想你可以说，我父母出城了，所以我一个人住公寓，我一个人住整栋房子。
Or even, she wants to eat the cake all to herself.
或者甚至，她想一个人吃掉整个蛋糕。
Very good. So, that's a very good phrase.
很好。所以这是一个非常好的短语。
And you can use it with any pronoun.
而且你可以和任何代词搭配使用。
Well, so the guy is explaining that I've always seen you as more than just a friend.
嗯，所以这个男生在解释，我一直把你视为不仅仅是朋友。
I've always seen you as...
我一直把你视为……
So, basically, it's the perception or the way you consider that person.
所以，基本上就是你对那个人的看法或考虑方式。
The way you think about that person.
你对那个人的想法。
So, I can say, I've always seen you as a good friend.
所以，我可以说，我一直把你视为好朋友。
I've always seen you as a leader.
我一直把你视为领导者。
Okay, so our last phrase is also the last thing we heard in the dialogue.
好的，我们最后一个短语也是我们在对话中听到的最后一句。
He said, are you willing to give me a shot?
他说，你愿意给我一次机会吗？
Are you willing to give me a shot?
你愿意给我一次机会吗？
To give me a shot.
给我一次机会。
Give me a shot.
Alright, I think we have some more examples of how we could use give me a shot in different situations.
好的，我想我们还有一些例子，说明如何在不同的情况下使用“给我一次机会”。
So, let's listen.
那么，我们来听听。
Example 1.
例子一。
I know I can do this drawing better. Just give me a shot.
我知道我能画得更好。就给我一次机会吧。
Example 2.
例子二。
The HR manager wasn't going to hire me, but he decided to give me a shot.
人力资源经理本来不打算雇用我，但他决定给我一次机会。
Okay, so when you give someone a shot, you take a chance, right?
好的，所以当你给某人一次机会时，你是在冒险，对吧？
Give that person or give an opportunity.
给那个人一个机会或提供一个机会。
Alright, so we don't know if she will give him a shot or not,
好的，所以我们不知道她会不会给他机会，
but why don't we listen to the dialogue once more to hear these phrases in action.
但我们再听一遍对话，听听这些短语在实际中的运用吧。
Hey, you're early. Where is everyone?
嘿，你来早了。其他人呢？
Well, I told them not to come. I made a reservation just for the two of us.
嗯，我告诉他们不用来了。我只订了我们两个人的位子。
I thought we could have a quiet evening all to ourselves.
我想我们可以独享一个安静的夜晚。
Oh, why?
哦，为什么？
Jennifer, there's something I want to ask you.
詹妮弗，我有件事想问你。
Sure, what is it?
当然，什么事？
Okay, here's the thing. I've always seen you as more than just a friend, and I can't take it anymore.
好吧，事情是这样的。我一直把你视为不仅仅是朋友，我再也受不了了。
I know you better than anyone. I know the pros and cons of your personality.
我比任何人都了解你。我知道你性格的优缺点。
I even know what side of the bed is yours. I think we would be great together, don't you?
我甚至知道你睡床的哪一边。我觉得我们在一起会很合适，你不觉得吗？
Are you serious? We've been friends for years. We can't just change that overnight.
你是认真的吗？我们做朋友好多年了。我们不能一夜之间就改变这个。
I know. I never had the guts to tell you until today.
我知道。我以前一直没勇气告诉你直到今天。
So what do you say? Are you willing to give me a shot?
那你觉得呢？你愿意给我一次机会吗？
Uh, uh...
呃，呃……
Alright, so an interesting dialogue, and it opens up a cultural point.
好吧，一个有趣的对话，它引出了一个文化点。
That's right. So in the dialogue, I'm going to ask you to give me a shot.
没错。所以在对话中，我要请你给我一次机会。
So in the dialogue, the guy was asking her if she would be his girlfriend, right?
所以在对话中，这个男生在问她是否愿意做他的女朋友，对吧？
Right, but I guess it's not very common, among adults at least, in English-speaking countries.
对，但我想这在英语国家，至少在成年人中，并不常见。
Yeah, we don't say like, okay, so please will you be my boyfriend now?
是的，我们不会说，好吧，请你现在做我的男朋友好吗？
Right, right, right. You would do that maybe in high school.
对，对，对。你可能在高中会这么做。
Yeah, but even then I think it's still a little funny.
是的，但即使那样，我觉得还是有点好笑。
I think for us, when we start to have romantic relationships, it just sort of happens naturally, right?
我觉得对我们来说，当我们开始有浪漫关系时，它只是自然而然地发生，对吧？
You never really have this conversation, will you be my boyfriend?
你从来没有真正进行过这个对话，“你愿意做我的男朋友吗？”
Right, I guess afterwards you just start talking about other things,
对，我想之后你们就开始谈论其他事情了，
which you just consider that you guys are already boyfriend and girlfriend.
然后你们就自然而然地认为你们已经是男女朋友了。
But there's no real... There's no official starting point.
但没有真正的……没有正式的起点。
Yeah, there's no official point that says, okay, now we are boyfriend and girlfriend.
是的，没有一个正式的时间点说，好了，现在我们就是男女朋友了。
Which is interesting because in other countries they do go through the formality of asking somebody to become their boyfriend.
这很有趣，因为在其他国家，他们确实会经历请求某人成为男朋友或女朋友的正式程序。
Yeah, but even, you know, like 20 or 30 years ago in English-speaking countries, you would do this.
是的，但即使在英语国家，比如二三十年前，你也会这么做。
Oh yeah, of course.
哦，是的，当然。
And it was called going steady.
而且那被称为“going steady”。
Going steady.
“Going steady”。
So you would ask, will you go steady with me?
所以你会问，“你愿意和我稳定交往吗？”
That means let's become a stable couple.
那意味着让我们成为稳定的情侣。
Exactly.
没错。
All right, so we want to hear your stories and well, how do you do it in your country?
好的，所以我们想听听你们的故事，嗯，在你们国家是怎么做的？
Do you ask someone out, do you maybe just give them the first kiss and that's an automatic yes?
你会约某人出去吗，或者也许你只是给他们初吻，那就自动表示同意了？
Well, I don't know, but I'm looking forward to hearing from our listeners.
嗯，我不知道，但我期待听到听众们的分享。
So guys, check out our website EnglishPod.com.
所以各位，请访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
You can leave your questions and comments there.
你可以在那里留下你的问题和评论。
All right, we'll see you guys there and until next time.
好的，我们那里见，下次再见。
Goodbye.
再见。
🎵 music playing 🎵
🎵 音乐播放中 🎵